

Marco Maida Computer scientist



13 August 1994



github.com/marcomaida



 $00 marcoma ida \\ 00 gmail.com$

About me ———

I am a computer scientist currently pursuing a Ph.D. at Max Planck Institute for Software Systems.

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember. In 2013, I started working professionally as a programmer. After three years, I decided to start a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer. Once I graduated, I moved to Kaiserslautern, Germany, and started a Joint Master and Ph.D program.

I completed all my master courses, and recently published my first paper.

Languages –

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am very fluent in English,

und ich spreche etwas Deutsch.

Extras —

I love camping and traveling with my bike: I often do the two together • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • Probably sometimes I talk too much • Striving not to be the smartest person in the room • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have nine years of professional experience in writing code. I am fluent in writing **Python**, **C#**, **C++**, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. During my seven years in the **industry**, I learnt to work on big code bases in large and small teams.

Having spent two years in **research**, I can study complicated problems and then design, implement, evaluate, document and finally present my solutions.

I am very **outgoing** and I **do well in teams**. Thanks to my experience in game development, I am used to collaborate with different professional figures and over time I developed a good taste for aesthetics and design.

Education

since 2019	Ph.D. student Real-time Systems group	Max Planck Institute for Software Systems
since 2019	Master in Computer Science	Technische Universität Kaiserslautern
2016-2019	Bachelor in Computer Science (110/100 cum laude)	Università degli studi di Torino
2015-2016	Game dev: Software Developmen Private school	t Event Horizon School

Experience

since 2019	Computer Science Researcher.	Max Planck Institute
------------	------------------------------	----------------------

I am currently working on Real-time Systems. My work is focused on timeliness certifications in safety-critical systems using formal verification (Coq) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux.

2016-2019 **Game developer.** 34BigThings

I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Nintendo Switch and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, tools and UIs.

2016 **Freelance Unity3D developer.** Teoresi, Choralia, Maserati I built an interactive visualization software and a learning game using

Unity3D. I shipped on mobile devices and browsers.

2013-2016 Software engineer. R.O. sr

I worked as a developer using C, C++, C# and SQL building solutions for glass processing factories. I covered many roles, including traveling to customers to sell, install and teach our software.

Projects

2021 **Poet - Automatic Proof Generation** Max Planck institute

I developed a tool that, given time data about a real-time system, produces machine-checked proofs bounding the worst-case scenario response time of each component of the system. An ongoing work publication has been recently accepted at RTSS2021, one of the top-class conferences for real-time systems.

2018 Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit. 34BigThings

I developed a Unity3D framework make the creation of production-ready casual games extremely fast, paired by a Python toolkit to execute bulk operations on the FMC games. With FMC, I, an artist, and a designer, developed ten production-ready games within a month.

(www.github.com/340penThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4. 34BigThings

I developed a framework that handles light effects on Razer's Chroma hardware that are coherent to what is happening in the game. This system is still used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)